A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Division, Latin America and the Caribbean, Jamaica and Mexico City Field Office Files FA612
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, International Division, Latin America and the Caribbean, Jamaica and Mexico City Field Office Files
1958-1974
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA612
8.9 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Contains correspondence, John S. Nagel files, reports, subject files, grant and proposal files.
Arrangement
Arranged in 5 series by file type.
Collection arrangement is as follows:
Series I. Chronological Correspondence Files, 1970 January-September
Series II. John S. Nagel (LAC Representative) Desk Files, 1966-1973
Series III. Reports, 1958-1969
Series IV. Subject Files, 1963-1973
Series V. Grant and Proposal Files, 1962-1974
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation maintained an office in Kingston, Jamaica from 1967 to 1970. The Kingston office administered the Foundation's program for Jamaica and the Caribbean region.
By 1979, the Foundation had issued over $13 million in grants for the Caribbean. The majority of the Foundation's Caribbean grantmaking focused on Jamaica, but it also provided support to the Domincan Republic, Barbados, and Trinidad. After it closed its Kingson office in 1970, the Foundation transferred responsibility for its Caribbean program to its Mexico City, Mexico office. The Foundation reduced its grantmaking to the Caribbean in the 1970s (The Ford Foundation in the Caribbean discussion notes, 1979, Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 13949-17726 (FA739F), Report 016709).
- Chronological Correspondence Files, 1970 January-September; I
  - Chronological Correspondence File -- Dr. W.K. Gamble, J.W. Trowbridge, E.G. Walks, M.A. Roche, 1970 January (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence File -- J.W. Trowbridge, E.G. Walks, M.A. Roche, 1970 February (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence File -- J.W. Trowbridge, E.G. Walks, M.A. Roche, 1970 March (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence File -- Dr. W.K. Gamble, J.W. Trowbridge, E.G. Walks, M.A. Roche, 1970 April (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence File -- J.W. Trowbridge, E.G. Walks, M.A. Roche, 1970 May (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence File -- J.W. Trowbridge, E.G. Walks, M.A. Roche, 1970 June (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence File -- J.W. Trowbridge, E.G. Walks, M.A. Roche, 1970 July (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence File -- J.W. Trowbridge, E.G. Walks, M.A. Roche, 1970 August (Box 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence File -- J.W. Trowbridge, E.G. Walks, M.A. Roche, 1970 September (Box 1)
- John S. Nagel (LAC Representative) Desk Files, 1966-1973; II
  - Board of Trustees, 1968-1971 (Box 2)
    Conditions Governing Access
    May contain restricted material.
  - Education in Latin America, 1970 (Box 2)
  - "Fair Share", 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Foreign Taxes, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Foundation Fellowships, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Foundation Programs in Europe -- Conference (2/24-25/1971), 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - International Urbanization Survey, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - McNamara, Robert -- Copenhagen Speech, Press Clippings and Articles Re: Response to Speech, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Overseas Development Self-Study: Questions for Representatives, Report for Venezuela, 1966 September 30 (Box 2)
  - Population -- General, 1968-1973 (Box 2)
  - Population Activities and USAID Grants (folder 1), 1968-1972 (Box 2)
  - Population Activities and USAID Grants -- Including Photograph from Marino Family Planning Evaluation Conference (folder 2), 1968-1972 (Box 2)
  - Program Advisor Candidates, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Program Related Investments (PRI) -- Including Report on PRI Two Years Later, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Resource Deployment Study -- Resource Bases, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Rome -- April Marino Conference 1970 and Additional Population Evaluation Program Materials, 1969-1972 (Box 2)
  - Tax Reform Act (H.R. 13270), 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Trips -- Bundy-Miller Visits to Latin America, 1970 October-November (Box 2)
  - Trips -- Visit of Mr. and Mrs. Miller to Latin America, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Trips -- Mr. Bell's Trip to Venezuela and Colombia, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Urbanization Survey -- Robin, John P., 1970-1971 (Box 2)
- Reports, 1958-1969; III
  - Argentina -- "Exploratory Mission to Latin America: Argentina" by Alfred Wolf, Reynold Carlson, Lincoln Gordon, Kalman Silvert, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Notes on Argentina" by Robert Alexander -- Re: Politics, 1959 February (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Government of the University of Buenos Aires" by Kalman H. Silvert, 1959 November (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Ford Foundation Mission to Argentina, Aug-Sep 1959, Summary of Recommendations", 1960 March (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Trip Notes, Argentina" by Alfred C. Wolf and Reynold Carlson, 1960 July (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Notes on Visit to Buenos Aires", 1960 July-August (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- Notes on Argentina and Peru -- Related to Dean Harrison's Argentina Visit, 1960 August (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Suggestions for Ford Foundation Support of Science and Technology in Argentina (Report of a Visit to Argentina in July-August 1960)" by C.V. Kidd, 1960 September 15 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Basic Science in Argentina, Mid 1960" by George R. Harrison, 1960 September 28 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- Trip Report, Sep-Oct 1960, 1960 September-October (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Manpower Survey Prepared for the Instituto Torcuato di Tella" by Robert L. Thomas, 1961 January (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "The Availability of Economists in the United Kingdom and France for Service Overseas" by Jo W. Saxe, 1961 August 2 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Education in the Field of Economic Development and Administration in Argentina and Chile" by William D. Carmichael, 1963 November (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- Library of Faculty of Exact and Natural Sciences at the University of Buenos Aires -- Two Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "University of Buenos Aires, School of Economics (Grant 62-235)" Memo from William D. Carmichael, 1965 April 2 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Economics in Argentina" by William D. Carmichael and Joseph Grunwald, 1965 June (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- Visit to Argentina, March-April 1967 -- Cotton, Albert, 1967 April (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Visit to Argentina, May 7th through May 19th, 1967" Memo from Abraham S. Fischler, 1967 May 29 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "Bariloche Report" by Thomas P. Nickell, Jr., 1967 June 26 (Box 3)
  - Argentina -- "General Reflections on a Visit to Argentina" by Richard N. Adams -- Re: Sociology and Anthropology, 1967 September 1 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Notes on Brazil" by Robert Alexander, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Exploratory Mission to Latin America - Brazil, 1959" by Alfred Wolf, Reynold Carlson, Lincoln Gordon (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Discussions on Brazil Held at Various U.S. Government Agencies, March 16-20, 1959" Memo from Nita Rous Manitzas, 1959 March 23 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Recommendations to Ford Foundation for Support of Economic Research Programs in Brazil" by Alfred C. Neal and Reynold E. Carlson, 1959 April 29 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Economic Growth in Brazil" by Reynold E. Carlson, 1959 May (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Ford Foundation Mission to Brazil, Summary of Recommendations" by Alfred Wolf, Lincoln Gordon, and Reynold Carlson, 1959 August (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "The Current Economic Situation in Brazil" by Reynold Carlson, 1959 December (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "American Cooperation with Brazilian Universities" by Robert J. Havighurst, 1960 April (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- Memorandum Re: Aeronautical Technicological Institute from E.E. Hagen, 1960 June (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Trip Notes, Brazil" by Alfred C. Wolf and Reynold Carlson, 1960 July (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Economics Teaching and Training of Economists in Brazil - An Appraisal with Recommendations" by Everett E. Hagen and William H. Nicholls, 1960 July (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Secondary Science Education in Brazil" by Karl Dittmer, Paul Klinge, and Arthur Roe, 1960 July (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Summary Report on Visit to Brazil -- Part A, Observations and Recommendations with Respect to Labor Market Research in Brazil" by C.V. Kidd, 1960 September (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Summary Report on Visit to Brazil -- Part B, Observations and Recommendations with Respect to Support of Science in Brazil" by C.V. Kidd, 1960 September (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- Correspondence Re: Visits to Science Centers from L. Grinter, 1960 September 6 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "A Report on a General Survey of the Libraries of the University of Sao Paulo" by Herman H. Fussler and Supplementary Statement, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Organizational Outline of the Proposed Institute of Statistics at the University of Sao Paulo" by Jerzy Neyman, 1961 March-April (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Notes on the Brazil Grant Program" by Sidney Mintz, 1961 June (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Basic Science in Brazil, Mid 1961" by George R. Harrison, 1961 September 1 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Observations upon Visits to Science Centers in Brazil, August 1962" by Charles V. Kidd, 1962 September (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "An Integrated Plan for Strengthening Graduate Education in Brazil" by Charles V. Kidd (confidential draft of a proposal), 1962 September 12 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Report of the Ford Foundation Survey Team on Pulic Administration Teaching and Research in Brazil" by Frederic N. Cleaveland, 1963 May 31 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Report on a Request for a Grant to Strengthen Graudate Education in the Sciences Throughout Brazil" by Charles V. Kidd, 1963 July 31 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Report on Mission to Survey Present Activities and Future Possibilities of ETV in Brazil" by James W. Armsey and John F. Baxter, 1963 August (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Instituto de Economia Rural Universidade Rural do Estado de Minas Gerais Vicosa, Minas Gerais, Brazil -- Current Status and Prospects" -- Progress Report by D. Woods Thomas, 1963 August (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Graduate Teaching and Research in Economics", 1963 September (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Report on the Rural University of the State of Minas Gerais", 1963 October (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Introductory Report on Brazilian Education with Special Reference to Secondary Schools" by George F.G. Little, 1964 March (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "A Study of Technical Education Problems in Brazil" by Ernest J. Simon, Albert E. French, Henry P. Adams, 1964 August 30 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Report on Trip to Brazil: August 2-September 3, 1964" by Nicholas Georgescu-Roegen, 1964 September (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "An Appraisal of the Needs of the Universidade Rural do Estado de Minas Gerais - Supplement 1", 1964 December 12 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Sao Paulo University CCTV Consultation Report" by Kenneth Christianson, 1964 December 15 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Activity Report of Ford Foundation Consultant to Advise on the Development of Post-Colegio Technical Education in Brazil" Memo from Henry P. Adams, 1965 April 12 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Political Science: Public Administration and Development in Brazil" by Peter Bell, 1965 September (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Report to the Ford Foundation on Support for Graduate Study in Science at the University of Brazil" by George R. Harrison, 1965 December 1 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Evaluation of the IRI Research Institute Animal Nutrition Center Program in Brazil and Related Agricultural Research and Educational Institutions" by Kenneth L. Turk, 1966 January 21 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Report on Visit to Rio de Janeiro to Explore Research Possibilities with BNDE and Sao Paulo School of Business Administration" by J.D. Nyhart, 1966 March (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Comments on Visit to Escola Americana, Rio de Janeiro, at the Request of the Ford Foundation" Memo from James D. MacConnell, 1966 April 5 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Notes on Engineering Education in Brazil" Memo from K.N. Rao, 1966 May 11 (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "A Suggested Program of BNDE-MIT Cooperation in Research and Management Training in the Brazilian National Development Banking System" and Related Correspondence, 1966 July (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- "Report of the Inter-American Development Bank Mission to Brazil" by Reuben Frodin, Charles F. Gosnell, K.N. Rao (English and Portuguese) and Related Documents, 1966 July-September (Box 3)
  - Brazil -- Georgescu-Roegen, Nicholas Letter Re: Visit about Vargas Support, 1967 July 3 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- "The French Caribbean" by Richard M. Morse, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- Report Re: Visit to Trinidad and Tobago and West Indies Information Sheets (report missing), circa 1959 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- Haiti Trip Report by Sidney Mintz, 1959 February (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- "University of Puerto Rico - Natural Sciences and Agriculture" by Paul Pearson, 1962 March 8 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- "Report of Activities in Connection with Santo Domingo Project for a Post-High School Business Institute" by Hamden L. Forkner, 1964 October 6 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- Report on Visit to Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic in Connection with Possible Support of APEC Plans for a Junior College of Business by Lionel H. Mercier, 1964 October 8 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- "Structures and Processes for Biomedical Research Policy in the British Caribbean" by C.V. Kidd, 1965 May 3 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- "The Political Situation in the Dominican Republic" by Robert A. Mayer, 1965 September 10 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- "Institute of Advanced Studies (ISA) Curriculum Development and Teacher Training" by Amalia Llabres de Charneco, 1965 November 30 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- "Trip to Dominican Republic, March 25-April 1, 1966" Memorandum from Morris A. Horowitz, 1966 April 12 (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- "The Dominican Crisis of 1965: An Annotated Bibilography" by Abraham Lowenthal, 1967 June (Box 3)
  - Caribbean -- Report Re: Jamaica Visit by Amos H. Hawley, 1969 February (Box 3)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "A Report to the Ford Foundation Concerning Program Possibilities in Latin America" by the Yale Group, 1958 June 10 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "Economic Research and Training in Latin America" by Richard Ruggles and Nancy Ruggles, 1960 March (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "Basic Science in Central America (Early 1962)" by George R. Harrison, 1962 May (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "Observations on Pan American School of Agriculture" by William K. Gamble, 1962 December (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "University Education and the Regional Concept in Central America" by Harold L. Enarson, 1963 August (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- Human Resources Study of Central America, An Interim Report" by Herbert J. Betz, 1963 September (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- Two Reports Re: Latin American Studies in the United States by Carl B. Spaeth (one co-written by John B. Howard), 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- Grants to National Universities of Honduras and Nicaragua, 1965 February (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- Memorandum Re: Seminar on Population Problems, 1965 March 23 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- Representatives Conference, Princeton -- Re: International Development, Development of the Social Sciences, and Training and Employment of "Middle Level" Technicians, 1965 November (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "Toward Strategies for Public Administration Development in Latin America" by John C. Honey, 1966 March (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "Agricultural Development in Latin America" Statement by Lowell S. Hardin before the International Finance Sub-Committee, House of Representatives, 1966 August 29 (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "Urban Planning and Development Centers in Latin America" by Guido G. Weigund and James H. Street, 1967 April (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "University Libraries - Appendix D - The Questionnaire to University Libraries" by Paul Bixler, 1967 June (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "The Challenge - A Political Economist's Views" by Byron L. Johnson -- Conference Paper, 1967 August-September (Box 4)
  - Central/Latin America General -- "The Role of the Humanities in Desarrollo: The Latin American Case" by William L. Reese, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- "Possibilities for Significant Studies of Land Reform in Chile" by Marion Clawson, 1960 April (Box 4)
  - Chile -- Correspondence/Report Re: Education Planning Committee from Paul Bulger, 1963 October 21 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- "A Report on Chilean Agriculture and Agricultural Education to the Ford Foundation" by S.O. Berg, L.E. Hanson, W.P. Martin, 1963 November (Box 4)
  - Chile -- Memorandum, Chile Education Planning Committee Re: Visit to Santiago, 1964 April 3 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- Report Re: Library Development at University of Concepcion by E.W. McDiarmid, 1964 April 29 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- Community Facilities Project in Chile (published booklet), 1966 February (Box 4)
  - Chile -- Correspondence/Report Re: Urban Development Advisory Program, 1967 January 10 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- "School of Business, Catholic University, Valparaiso", 1967 May 15 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- Consultant's Report Re: Education, "Project in Curricular Reform and Teaching Retraining" by Michael Chiappetta, 1967 May-June (Box 4)
  - Chile -- "Trip Report for a Study of the Chemical Engineering Program at the Universidad Tecnica Federico Santa Maria" by John W. Tierney, 1967 September 6 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- Memorandum Re: Chile and Urban and Regional Planning from Ralph A. Gakenheimer, 1967 September 13 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- "Trip Report for a Study of the Electrical Engineering Program at the Universidad Tecnica Federico Santa Maria" by Howard B. Hamilton, 1967 September 28 (Box 4)
  - Chile -- "Trip Report - A Study of Engineering Programs at the Universidad Tecnica Federico Santa Maria" by H.E. Hoelscher, 1967 October 19 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Ford Foundation Mission to Colombia" by Richard Morse, Robert Wickham, Alfred Wolf, 1960 June (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Political and Economic Profile of Colombia - Ford Foundation Mission to Colombia" by Richard Morse, Robert Wickham, Alfred Wolf, 1960 June (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Manpower Problems and Policies in Colombia" by J.F. Wellemeyer (draft and final copies included), 1960 December-1961 January (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Colombia - Martin Kriesberg's Role" by George A. Graham, 1962 August 27 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Report to the Ford Foundation Concerning the Developments and Prospects at the University of Antioquia, Medellin, Colombia" by Francic T. Bonner, Sidney Gelber, Richard M. Morse, 1963 April (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "The Armsey-Morrill Mission to the Universidad del Valle, Cali, Colombia" Memo from J.L. Morrill, 1963 August 12 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Review of Agricultural Progress in Colombia" by Robert Wickham, circa 1964 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "ICA's Current Program in Colombia and Possible Areas Where the Ford Foundation Might Render Meaningful Assistance" Memo from J. Norman Efferson, 1964 July 24 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Report to the [Ford] Foundation on Consultation with the University of the Andes, Bogota, Colombia" by James S. Triolo, 1964 September 21 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Review of Colombian Population Program Developments since November 12, 1964 and Projections until Summer 1966" by Dieter Zschock, 1965 July 1 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Progress Report on the Development Program of the University of the Andes, Bogota, March 20-23, 1966" by James S. Triolo, 1966 March (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Trip Report" by John M. Hunter, 1966 December (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Report on a Trip to Bogota and Cali" by Arthur J. Coutu, 1967 March (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Confidential Report of Visit to Colombia, March 17-April 3, 1967 to Study the Development of Selected University Faculties of Education" by Robert N. Bush, 1967 April (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- Correspondence Re: University of Valle, Javeriana, Antioquia from H. Thomas James, 1967 April 13 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "Universidad Nacional - Consultation Visit Concerning Centralized Cataloging in the Libraries" by Imogene Hixson, 1967 July (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- "The Faculty of Human Sciences National University of Colombia" by William D. Carmichael and Peter D. Bell, 1967 July 17 (Box 4)
  - Colombia -- University of Antioquia -- Library Development, 1967 September 25 (Box 4)
  - Costa Rica -- "Faculty of Agronomy, University of Costa Rica, Report on Visit to the Faculty" by William K. Gamble, 1962 November 13 (Box 4)
  - Costa Rica -- "Report on a Project to Expand Economic Research and Improve the Training of Economists at the University of Costa Rica" by Victor L. Urquidi, 1963 March (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "Report on the Proposed Integrated Agricultural Institute at Chapingo, Mexico", 1962 July (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "Agricultural Program" by J.S. Nagel, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "Comments and Recommendations on the Agricultural Economics Center" by Earl O. Heady, 1964 April (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "A Study and Evaluation - State of Mexico Agricultural Extension Service", 1964 October (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "Progress Report Number Three on Study and Evaluation Recommendations", 1966 February 11 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "Program for the Centro Nacional de Productividad in Management Development and Organization Improvement in Industrial Enterprises" by Emmett Wallace, 1966 December 2 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- Correspondence Re: Ford Foundation Mission to Mexico, 1966 December 27 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "Graduate Education in Management at UNAM (National Autonomous University of Mexico)" by William D. Carmichael, Richard M. Cyert, Ezra Solomon, 1967 February 20 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- Report Re: Mexican Institute of Social Studies by Reuben Hill, 1967 March 17 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- Trip Report by Bernard P. Queenan, 1967 June 10 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "Notes on Mexican Visit" Re: Anthropology, 1967 September (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "The Mexican Library" and Related Correspondence/Letter of Transmittal by Paul Bixler, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Mexico -- "Library and Information Services in Mexico" by Carl M. White, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Peru -- Report Re: National Engineering University, 1963 April 19 (Box 4)
  - Peru -- "The Program in Peru - Report on its Current Status" by Peter Fraenkel, 1964 January 8 (Box 4)
  - Peru -- Report Re: Population Development in Peru, 1965 March (Box 4)
  - Peru -- "Report to the Ford Foundation, Evaluation of and Recommendation for the Faculty of Engineering at the Catholic University of Peru" by Sidney A. Guralnick, 1966 July 19 (Box 4)
  - Peru -- "Suggestions Concerning Agricultural Budgeting and Programming in Peru" by L.S. Hardin and F.F. Hill, 1967 May 30 (Box 4)
  - Peru -- Report Re: Lima Visit and Education (May 16-17, 1967) by Bernard P. Queenan, 1967 June 5 (Box 4)
  - Peru -- Report Re: Visit to Study Inter-University Council by Herman B. Wells, 1967 August 17 (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- "Venezuela Report" by R.S. Wickham, 1962 May (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- Record of Conversation with Dr. Aristides Calvani of Universidad Catolica Andres Bello -- Conversation Reports and Suggestions, 1962 July (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- Report Re: Educational Planning by O.M. Wilson, 1963 September 9 (Box 4)
  - Venezuela -- "Seminar on Educational Planning, August 3-7, 1964, Caracas, Venezuela" Memo by Harold W. Stoke, 1964 August 12 (Box 4)